Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Three boys and a man standing in front of the door of Yesil (Green) Mosque, or Mosque of Mehmed I, Bursa, Turkey. 26.8 x 20.9 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Green Mosque, Bursa; Bursa, Turkey; Mosques; Doors/Entrances; Hats; Men; Children; Boys; Arabic Writing; Religious Sites; Children; Boys; Group Portraits
- The Golden Horn, Istanbul, taken from the Eyup Cemetery. 21 x 26.9 cm, 1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Boats/Ships; Water; Constantinople; Rivers; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; The Golden Horn/Haliç
- Abide-i Hurriyet, Monument of Liberty, Sisli (N. 952 Monument desc martyres de la Liberté). 26.8 x 20.8 cm, 1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Monument of Liberty; Architecture; Doors/Entrances; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Sisli, Istanbul, Turkey; Monuments/Memorials; Fez/Tarboush
- Haydarpasa Ingiliz Mezarligi (British Cemetery), Crimean War Memorial, Haidar Pasha Cemetery, Uskudar, Istanbul. 26.9 x 20.9 cm, 1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Cemeteries; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Monuments/Memorials; Uskudar, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing
- Yildiz Palace, Istanbul (N. 546, Palais Yildiz). 20.7 x 26.7 cm, 1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Yildiz Palace; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Buildings; Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Palaces; Photographic Prints; French Writing
- Golden Gate, Yedikule, Istanbul. Identical print to ref 111. 20.8 x 26.8 cm, 1898 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing; Buildings
- Kucuksu Pavilion (formerly Goksu Pavilion) and the Mihrisah Valide Sultan Fountain (also Kucuksu Fountain). 19.8 x 26.5 cm, 1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Buildings; Architecture; Fountains; Kucuksu Palace; Outdoors; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Palaces; Kiosks/Kushk
- Entrance to the Black Sea from the Bosphorus. 20.8 x 26.8 cm, 1890 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Seas; Istanbul, Turkey; Rivers; Water; Bosphorus; Black Sea; Landscapes
- Galata Tower, Istanbul, Turkey. 24.6 x 18.1 cm, Circa 1900 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Flags; Constantinople; Buildings; Architecture; Albumen Prints; Galata Tower; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey
- Galata Tower, Istanbul, Turkey. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Outdoors; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Galata Tower; Flags; Constantinople; Buildings; Architecture; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Turkish Writing
- Woman wearing pearls and a veil with a dark shawl, holding a hand fan. 25.2 x 18.6 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Hand Fans; Jewelry; Women; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Head Covers/Veils
- Woman standing in a dress, arms akimbo, with a shisha. 23.5 x 19.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Constantinople; Hats; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Embroidery; Jewelry; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Women
- Woman wearing pearls, a veil, and a dark shawl holding a hand fan trimmed with feathers. 23.8 x 18.4 cm, Circa 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Women; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Furnishings; Hand Fans; Head Covers/Veils; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Men washing before prayer at ablution fountains at the Suleymaniye Mosque in Istanbul, Turkey. 18.5 x 25.5 cm, Circa 1890; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites; Religious Ceremony; Men; Mosques; Fountains; Suleymaniye Mosque; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Turkish Writing
- Ceremony at Yildiz Palace, Istanbul, Turkey. 19.4 x 24.9 cm, 1898; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Streets/Roads; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Military/Soldiers; Architecture; Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Yildiz Palace; Men; Palaces; Group Portraits
- The Battlefields of Toski, near Abu Simbel, Egypt. 20.2 x 26.3 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Toski, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Wars; Men; Deserts; Landscapes
- Mihrisah Valide Sultan Fountain (also Kucuksu Fountain, Asia Freshwater Fountain), a shepherd with six sheep, and a street vendor selling food. 19.1 x 25.1 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Fountains; Water; Hats; Street Vendors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Constantinople; Food; Istanbul, Turkey; Animals; Outdoors; Kucuksu Palace; Bosphorus; Palaces; Sheep; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush
- Two ferries arriving at a port on a river in Egypt. 20.1 x 26.2 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Lakes; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Water; Boats/Ships; Nile River
- Steamboats traveling on the Nile River. Voyage of Sultan Abdulaziz. 20.1 x 26.2 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Egypt; Water; Lakes; Rivers; Nile River; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships; Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- Walls of the Yedikule Fortress, Istanbul, Turkey. 19.5 x 25.4 cm, Circa 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings
- Prince Şehzade Yusuf Izzeddin (1857-1916) as a boy, during his visit to Egypt. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Swords/Knives; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Uniforms; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Weapons; Boys; Children; Royalty; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; French Writing; Yusuf İzzeddin, Şehzade, Prince, son of Abdülaziz, Sultan of the Turks,, 1857-1916
- Şehzade Mehmed Seyfeddin Efendi (1874-1927) as a young boy, standing with a sword. 16.3 x 11.2 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Boys; Children; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Furnishings; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Carpets/Rugs; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Weapons; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Royalty; French Writing; English Writing; Ottoman Writing; Mehmed Seyfeddin, Şehzade, 1874-1927
- "Sifahiye" (hospital) doorway to the Gevher Nesibe complex, Antalya, Turkey. 18 x 12.9 cm, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Antalya, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Doors/Entrances; Buildings; Turkish Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Gevher Nesibe Hospital Complex; Photographic Prints
- President Mustafa Kemal Ataturk (1881-1938) and, on the right, Prime Minister Ismet Pasha (1884-1973) introducing the new turkish alphabet in Kayseri, Anatolia, Turkey (linked ref155). 9.1 x 14 cm, 20 September 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Smoking; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Men; Anatolia, Turkey; Uniforms; Pasha; Kayseri,Turkey; Political Leadership; Group Portraits; Police; Facial Hair; Cigarettes; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; İnönü, Mustafa İsmet, 1884-1973; Atatürk, Mustafa Kemal, 1881-1938
- Turkish Prime Minister Ismet Pasha giving a speech at a ceremony for the opening of rail service to Kayseri, Turkey. 11.4 x 17.1 cm, 29 May 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Kayseri,Turkey; Hats; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Speeches; Flags; Ceremonies; Group Portraits; Transportation; Railways; Ottoman Writing; Crowds; Audiences/Spectators; İnönü, Mustafa İsmet, 1884-1973
- Panorama of Kayseri. The clock tower, Grand Bazaar and Kayseri Castle. 9.9 x 17 cm, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Grand Bazaar; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kayseri,Turkey; Landscapes; Forts/Castles; Architecture; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Clocks/Watches; Markets
- President Mustafa Kemal Ataturk (1881-1938) and, on the right, Prime Minister Ismet Pasha (1884-1973) introducing the new Turkish alphabet in Kayseri (linked ref152). 17 x 12.3 cm, 20 September 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Hats; Uniforms; Smoking; Kayseri,Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkish Writing; Men; Political Leadership; Group Portraits; Police; Facial Hair; Cigarettes; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Photographic Prints; İnönü, Mustafa İsmet, 1884-1973; Atatürk, Mustafa Kemal, 1881-1938
- Children at Haci Mansur Primary School in Kayseri, Turkey celebrating Republic Day wearing uniform or regional Turkish dress. 11.9 x 17.1 cm, 29 October 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Hats; Buildings; Regional/National Dress; Schools/Education; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kayseri,Turkey; Parades/Processions; Girls; Boys; Children; Banners; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Atatürk, Mustafa Kemal, 1881-1938
- Self-portrait of photographer Hayri T. Tolgay. 18 x 12.9 cm, Circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Individual Portraits; Men; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Turkish Writing
- Street vendors from Port Said, Egypt. Two boys sitting and one girl standing, the girl carrying produce on her head and the boys with vegetables in a basket in front of them. On reverse side of ref159. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Fez/Tarboush; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Hats; Albumen Prints; Street Vendors; Boys; Women; Children; Port Said, Egypt; Group Portraits; Food; Head Covers/Veils
- Woman sitting on a studio boulder fixture, holding a piece of pottery, leaning on a wide-bottomed amphora. On reverse side of ref158. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Pottery; Women; Egypt; Painted Backdrops
- Woman reclined on a pillow, holding a hand fan with a tall pipe at her feet. French writing at the bottom: "Arab woman having her siesta in a villa near the Pyramides." 19.9 x 26.8 cm, Undated; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  French Writing; Hand Fans; Egypt; Women; Jewelry; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Hats; Smoking; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles
- Hand-colored photograph of a man in a suit standing on the bank of a creek in the woods. 16.6 x 12.5 cm, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Paintings; Turkey; Outdoors; Water; Rivers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits
- Tomb with intricately carved wood panels. 23.6 x 31 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Arabic Writing; Tombs/Mausoleums; Furnishings; Arabic Calligraphy; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Coffins/Caskets; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites
- Three women and a young boy standing under a tree on the banks of the Nilufer River, Gecit Korusu, Bursa, Turkey. 30 x 25 cm, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Water; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Hats; Boys; Children; Turkish Writing; Women; Rivers; Outdoors; Group Portraits
- A man and woman standing under a tree on the Nilufer River with a stone bridge in the background, Gecit Korusu, Bursa, Turkey. 30 x 24.9 cm, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Hats; Women; Men; Bridges; Rivers; Outdoors; Turkish Writing; Water; Photographic Prints
- Three women, a man and a boy standing under the Nilufer Bridge, spanning the Nilufer River in Bursa, Turkey. Identified on the label as one of the first Turkish architectural monuments in Bursa. 23.4 x 29.8 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Turkish Writing; Bridges; Bursa, Turkey; Men; Women; Children; Boys; Hats; Water; Rivers; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
- Self-portrait of Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu standing in front of the State Art and Sculpture Museum in Ankara, Turkey. 31 x 22.8 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Men; Ankara, Turkey; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Buildings; Architecture; Museums
- Green Mosque in Bursa, Turkey, in the snow. 23 x 17 cm, Undated (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Snow; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Mosques; Green Mosque, Bursa; Religious Sites
- Street cobbler in Eyup. 17.9 x 22.7 cm, 1905 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Turbans; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Doors/Entrances; Street Vendors; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Hats; Workers; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A Street in Bursa. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, 1908 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Docks/Piers/Jetties; Doors/Entrances; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Houses; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
- Eight soldiers of the Ottoman army ski association on the Caucasian front (linked ref181). 17.8 x 24 cm, 1913 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  World War I; Wars; Group Portraits; Animals; Snow Skis; Uniforms; Turkey; Snow; Dogs; Hats; Men; Caucasus; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Wars
- Carved wood minbar from a Turkish mosque. 31 x 23.3 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkey; Religious Sites; Mosques
- Man standing with large decorated tile. 30 x 23.2 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Men; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkey; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Hats; Fez/Tarboush
- Arabic script carved into wood panels. 30 x 23.2 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Architecture; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Furnishings; Arabic Calligraphy; Art; Arabic Writing; Religious Sites
- State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey, under construction. 22.8 x 31 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Buildings; Museums; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Construction; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara; Ankara, Turkey; Architecture
- Hand-colored photograph of Yeni Kaplica ("new spa") thermal bath, Bursa, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Architecture; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Landscapes; Turkish Writing
- Theater hall inside the State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Doors/Entrances; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara; Architecture; Ankara, Turkey; Theater; Museums
- Selimiye Mosque, in Edirne, Turkey. View from across the nearby Tundza (Tunca) River. 23.3 x 31 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Edirne, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tundzha River; Religious Sites; Selimiye Mosque; Architecture; Buildings; Mosques
- Self-portraits of Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu, the center portrait was taken in his studio Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi. 20.9 x 27.4 cm, 1915; Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi, Turkey (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Fur Garments; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair
- Woman in a dark dress and eyeglasses, emerging through a divide in a curtain. 17.6 x 12.3 cm, Undated; Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi, Turkey (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Individual Portraits; Women; Turkey; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Hats; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography
- Woman in a black headscarf, sitting on a chair. 17.8 x 12.3 cm, Undated; Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi, Turkey (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Five soldiers of the Ottoman army ski association and two Berg Forer mountain dogs sitting on the side of the Ararat mountain during the Caucasian campaign in World War I (linked ref170). 9 x 14 cm, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Animals; Military/Soldiers; Dogs; Snow; Snow Skis; Guns; Uniforms; Erzurum, Turkey; Caucasus; Turkish Writing; Wars; Ottoman Writing; World War I; Hats; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Men; Weapons; Facial Hair; Guns; Hats; Wars
- View of Nusretli, Yozgat. Berggren. 31.6 x 36.5 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Yozgat, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Countryside/Rural; Landscapes
- View over the Grand Bazaar. Prince Islands and Sea of Marmara. 29.8 x 37.9 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Bosphorus; Prince Islands, Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Grand Bazaar; Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Sea of Marmara; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Religious Sites; Buildings; Markets
- Religious procession in an Ottoman village. 19.9 x 25.6 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gatherings; Religious Ceremony; Group Portraits; Buildings
- Group photo of fifteen Ottoman military men in front of a fence. Man seated in the center wearing binoculars. Man seated at the far left wearing a riding crop. 29.6 x 35.5 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Binoculars; Uniforms; Hats
- Rifat in Samsun. "To my dear uncle Ziya Bey". 29.6 x 35.7 cm, 28 June 33 (1917) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Samsun, Turkey; Maps; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Turkish Writing; Regional/National Dress; Ottoman Writing; Men; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Uniforms
- Group portrait of three women and two men. Woman in the center holding a Turkish oud and man in the bottom right holding a shisha pipe. Photo ripped diagonally on the bottom left. 29 x 39.3 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Musical Instruments; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Women; Men; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Facial Hair; Turbans; Books; Prayer Beads; Hats; Swords/Knives; Embroidery; Jewelry
- Port Said, Egypt. 27.9 x 35.1 cm., Undated; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Landscapes; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Port Said, Egypt; Buildings
- A portrait of a man sitting in front of a printed backdrop with a girl on his lap, a boy standing to his left. 31.4 x 25.8 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Military/Soldiers; Painted Backdrops; Children; Turkey; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Weapons; Men; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Toys; Fez/Tarboush; Boys; Girls; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Hats
- Procession of men, horses, and carriages facing to the right with men on the right-hand side facing the center. 29.9 x 36.2 cm., Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Horses; Men; Animals; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Military/Soldiers; Carriages/Coaches; Group Portraits
- Group photo of Ottoman military officials and two young boys standing underneath an archway with the Ottoman flag hanging inside the entrance to the left. 30 x 35.5 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Children; Facial Hair; Weapons; Ottoman Writing; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Military/Soldiers; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Turkey; Arabic Writing; Men; Hats
- A group of men on horseback in regional dress and an Ottoman soldier in uniform standing with a sword in the center foreground. 25 x 30 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Horses; Regional/National Dress; Women; Men; Ottoman Writing; Weapons; Animals; Turkey; Group Portraits; Fez/Tarboush; Crowds; Outdoors; Hats
- Group of soldiers and government officials praying, standing at the top and base of the exterior staircase leading to the second floor terrace of a brick building. 25 x 30 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Facial Hair; Flags; Uniforms; Baghdad, Iraq; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair; Religious Ceremony; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Praying; Fez/Tarboush; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits; Hats
- Large group of men standing to the sides of a path entering a building with striped guard towers on either side of the doorway. The men are praying, led by a religious figure in the center and a band with a drum and brass intruments stand to the right. 30 x 35.1 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Turkey; Weapons; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Religious Ceremony; Praying; Military/Soldiers; Musical Instruments; Group Portraits; Ottoman Writing
- A group of soldiers sit in front of their barracks, whilst a speech is given by an imam. A group of men, including German military leaders, are gathered on the right in front of a small mosque. 29.5 x 35 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Religious Ceremony; Praying; Uniforms; Buildings; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Men; Architecture; Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Speeches; Religious Sites
- A line of soldiers are reviewed by visiting military leaders. 29.5 x 35 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Swords/Knives; Parades/Processions; Religious Ceremony; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Turkey; Men; Regional/National Dress; Albumen Prints; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Priests/Clergymen; Group Portraits
- Cavalry class at the Ottoman Military College. Turkish writing on back reads: ("Pangalti Mekteb-i Harbiye (Ottoman Military College) 1918"). 29.5 x 30 cm, 5 June 1918 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Military/Soldiers; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Hats; Uniforms; Ottoman Writing; Turkish Writing
- Dr. William Goodell (1792–1867), a Christian missionary. 28.5 x 25.8 cm, 1860; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Studio Photography; Bow Ties; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Men; Albumen Prints; Turkey
- Dirt road bending to the right in the distance. The road is on the side of a hill with trees on both sides. 23.7 x 27.6 cm, Undated (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Outdoors; Outdoors; Streets/Roads; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes